YESHWANTH NELLIKANTI



QUALIFICATION SUMMARY

4 years of experience as **Business Analyst** with knowledge of the business process in the Insurance domain at various software's like Policy Management System, Agency Management System and Wealth Management Accelerator.

Demonstrated functional leadership strong Interpersonal skills and Communication skills facilitating training sessions and problem-solving skills.

A thorough understanding of SDLC including but not limited to various concepts such as Requirements gathering, development of web-based applications, Configuration, User Acceptance Testing, Test Cases, Test Scenarios and SQL queries.

TECH SKILLS

Python HTML/CSS/XML Java Script SQL Server, MY SQL Tableau

Microsoft Office (PowerPoint, VISIO, Outlook)

EDUCATION

Master's Degree, MSCIS

University of South Alabama Mobile, AL | 2019 - 2021

Graduate Coursework

Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Web Technologies and Knowledge Modeling, Data Mining, Big Data Analytics, Data Warehouse, Cyber Physical Security, Artificial Intelligence Theory and Programming, Distributed Systems, Database Management, Information System Analysis Design.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PROFESSIONAL BUSINESS ANALYST

DXC TECHNOLOGY | DATA HUB | AMERITAS | 2018-2019

- Communicated with clients to gather/document information of their system development/business model requirements and specifications.
- Designed a centralized database through the requirements and migrated their data from DOS to MS SQL Server.
- > Brainstormed the project requirements, strategies to technical team and quality analysis team by developing basic conceptual data, Mock-up screens, User Stories, process models, and data dictionaries.
- Contributed in planning, designing business process, formulating recommendations to enhance the business and supported business activities.
- Work on new Change Requests received from clients by understanding and documenting the necessary changes and transmit about it to the respective teams with few business scenarios.

BUSINESS ANALYST

CSSI PVT. LTD | VUE Distribution MANAGEMENT SUITE | METFLIFE & AFLAC | 2017-2018

- Involved in requirement gathering and Subject Matter Expert (SME) for data migration activities, assuring quality deliverables to the client.
- ➤ Developed Functional Specifications documents, User Manual, Business Requirement document and design documents for new Change Requests.
- > Implemented UX/UI changes thus increasing goal conversion rate by 60% while working in agile environment
- > Acted as bridging link between the technical and functional aspects by giving recommendations based on requirements
- Involved in creating test cases ensuring that the developed software performs as detailed by the business requirements and tested various functions and applications as an end user.
- > Created demos and status reports to communicate upcoming enhancements, progress on requests in development, and future technology plans to implementation groups.
- Involved in Managing and tracking the product issues and enhancements using the internal trackers

ASSOCIATE BUSINESS ANALYST

EBIX INDIA PVT.LTD | LIFE INSURANCE, 401(K) PLAN, PRESALES | JOHN HANCOCK | 2015-2017

- Meticulously comprehended the Process flow to have a clear understanding of the business requirements and associated system workflow.
- Conducted JAD sessions for better understanding new business model, refining of requirements and additional functionalities by coordinating with multiple teams.
- Worked as a configurator using components such as Business rule Engine in different modules like Users, Work allocation, User roles, Requirements, Workflow, Mandatory validations.
- Worked on Application Screen Changes, Data Saving and retrieving data from Application Screens.
- Defining Solution Scope in a form of the Feature list with complete coverage of all the requirements in RFP on the level of the details efficient/required for estimations. Based on the RFP input materials quality and timeframe it will be ballpark/high level or detailed Feature list
- Provided project manager with regular status, updates assisting the overall project management initiative.